ANIL ENES CALIS

SRE & DevOps Engineer

<u>anilenescalis@gmail.com</u>

1+90 (530) 350 26 52 **In** linkedin.com/in/anilenescalis

♥ Istanbul, Turkey

As an SRE and DevOps engineer with 1 year experience, I have background in managing and continually optimizing container technologies, cloud platforms and on-premise systems. I have been effective in integrating new technologies and open-source software by prioritizing the security of the systems. In addition, I am a strong person in close cooperation with other engineers, active listening, systematic communication and leadership skills.

EDUCATION

Eskisehir Osmangazi University

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineer

Sep. 2014 - Oct. 2020 Eskisehir, Turkey

Window Cleaning Robot Design and Implementation (TUBITAK 2209-B Industry Focused Undergraduate Graduation

EXPERIENCES

LC Waikiki Sep. 2021 - Current

SRE & DevOps Engineer

Istanbul, Turkey

- Managing of Cloud Platforms and Container Orchestration Platforms
- Improving Automation for Systems
- Installing Open-Source Application and Monitoring Tools
- Linux and Windows Server Configuration
- Experiencing in troubleshooting and Monitoring of Applications using Golden Signals
- Basic knowledge of firewall, load balancer and network

Itelligence Business Solutions

SAP Basis Intern

Aug. 2020 - Sep. 2020 Istanbul, Turkey

- SAP Installation Pre-Configuration for Windows
- Creating Users and Authorities
- **Providing Security Management**
- Generating Execution Report RTCCTOOL
- Performing SAP Monitoring and Performance Controls

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Kubernetes Docker Ansible **Terraform**

Redis RabbitMQ **Elastic Stack Prometheus**

Grafana IIS **Zabbix AppDynamics**

Microsoft Azure **GCP VMware**